Matthew Cheung

mcheung26.vercel.app

linkedin.com/in/mcheung26

cheunm23@mcmaster.ca

technical skills		
Languages: Frameworks/Libraries: Tools:	Python, Java, JavaScript, C/C++, HTML/CSS, Bash, Verilog, Lua React.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Linux, TensorFlow Figma, AutoCad, Adobe XD, MATLAB, Canva, Visio	
projects		
Tetris Game + Al Python, Pygame 011/2022 - Present	Developed Tetris in Python through Pygame with an AI that plays it. Leveraged OOP principles to implement rotation, block types, and logic in the program.	
Portfolio Website CSS/HTML, Tailwind CSS 09/2021 - Present	Created a responsive personal website using HTML/CSS, and Tailwind CSS framework. Designed and prototyped website on Figma, focusing on optimizing user experience and reflecting personal style.	
McMaster Projects Verilog, Intel Quartus, Python, Quanser Labs 09/2020 - 04/2021	Designed complex logic systems through Intel's DE1-SoC Board with Verilog, including ALUs, signal taps and hardware compatibility.	
	Developed a high-fidelity recycling-transport system using Python on Raspberry Pi's, simulated in Quanser Labs Software.	
experience		
Technical Coding Instructor Code Ninjas 06/2022 - 09/2022	Conducted one-on-one accelerated programing sessions in a competitive summer camp, measuring and tracking data. Topics included Java, Python, C++ and JavaScript.	
	Designed and conducted engaging workshops for members to participate in, with over 65% of my students enrolling my additional programs.	
Program Coordinator Marianne Home 09/2018 - 12/2020	Effectively led a team of 5 members to plan and execute interactive and engaging events for clients, keeping a 100% punctuality record and learning professionalism and work responsibility in a high pressure environment.	
education		
McMaster University Bachelor of Applied Science Software Engineering 09/2021 - 04/2022	Coursework of human-computer interaction, the design and application of efficient and reliable software, and subsequently the operation and maintenance of the programs.	
courses + interests		
Data Structures & Algorithms, Object-Orientated (Java), Computer Architecture	Interaction and visual design, research & strategy, information architecture, machine learning	In love w/ philosophy, psychology, visual arts, piano, reading, badminton, video games, and so much more.